Hello everyone, welcome back to tradition another new tutorial topic. So today I can create for the
order of class in the post-grid skill and this allows us to sort the result set written by
selected statement based on the specified column okay. So first of all simply understand this
explain for the post-grid SQL order by we can use sort the result set ascending or the descending
order based on the one or more column it is powerful tool for organizing data in the meaningful way
okay. So first of all here I create the first example for sorting the ascending order okay. So here
use for the simple on table and now here define use perfectly for the order by group okay. So here
first of all I can just type the select then insert okay for the multiple multiplication sign and
then I can select for suppose here I use for the employee so now just use for the in this table
okay. So now just type for the employees okay and then going to the next step and here I can use
perfectly the order by class and here type this and last name okay. So I hope you understand it
and simply order by class to solve reason to set ascending order based on the last name column okay.
So here I can select all and only to click and here we can see here the output for
in this operation successful and the post-grid skill written for the all row sorted by
alphabetically by the last name in the ascending order okay. So I hope you understand it.
So now move on for another example and here I can create sorting in the descending order okay.
So now here I can use for the order by class to sort the result set in the descending order
based on here now I can type for this and here I can create suppose like
for now here I can use simply for the age okay so now just try so first of all here I can use
for the employee and now here I can use for the order by the age column okay. So now define
and perfectly and here I can also put the age is it. So here define for the age is the descending
column. So now just try the define perfectly and here selecting an execute and you can see here perfectly
create for the age column for the descending order okay and in this session I can also create this
example complete and the post-grid the skill written all the rows sorted in the date in the
descending order sorry not the date the age in the descending order and there also use for the
multiple column sorted based for the order by class so here I can simply just read this
and now here first sorted for suppose like first I can use the department okay. So
department and also here I can use for the salary column okay so now just perfectly type this is the
salary and this is the perfect and here the department so just check for the DE
department department okay you can hear the perfect department salary in the descending
and department ascending order then by the salary in the descending order and here now
just select and then execute. Now you can see here perfectly printed first on the
department column and this is the age column okay. So this operation is successful and
post-grid written all the sorted department in the ascending order within the age column okay.
So here in this session perfectly lastly here for another example suppose like for sorting is the
expression okay so here just for increment salary and so now just remove for the department
and here I can use for the multiplication sign for the 1.1 okay and now just apply so here I can
select and execute and you can see here perfectly update for the salary range okay for the salary
column okay. So I hope you understand this example and here the salary increase for 10% and this
operation is completely successful and the post-grid is clearly done the update results sheet okay.
So here I hope you perfectly understand and in this session perfectly done okay so I hope
you perfectly understand and enjoy this session so thank you for watching and happy coding.